Finding Aid for Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research publications, 1962-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research publications 1962-2006
Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research.
0071 Bimu 2
Publications of the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research. Includes annual reports, catalogs, manuals and newsletters. Contains the publications of the National Archive of Computerized Data on Aging, National Archive of Criminal Justice Data, and National Institute of Justice. Contains bulletins and syllabi from Summer Course in Quantitative Methods
6 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (donor # 8741 )
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The ICPSR publications open without restriction.
For historical note, please consult the finding aid for Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research records.
The Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research Publications includes annual reports, catalogs, manuals and newsletters. The record group also includes publications of the National Archive of Computerized Data on Aging, National Archive of Criminal Justice Data, and National Institute of Justice. The Publications are divided into two series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications.
Subjects:
Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research.; Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research.; International Relations Archive.; National Archive of Computerized Data on Aging (U.S.); National Archive of Criminal Justice Data.; National Criminal Justice Archive and Information Network.; National Institute of Justice (U.S.)
Contributors:
Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research.; International Relations Archive.; National Archive of Computerized Data on Aging (U.S.); National Archive of Criminal Justice Data.; National Criminal Justice Archive and Information Network.; National Institute of Justice (U.S.); Summer Course in Quantitative Methods.
Genre Terms:
Annual reports.; Catalogs.; Manuals.; Newsletters.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series contains annual reports from 1962 until the present, brochures, general catalogs of the ICPSR's holdings and two data preparation manuals, one from 1980 and one from 1997. The series also includes newsletters. Informational Mailings was published from 1976 until 1981, and was discontinued shortly after the ICPSR Bulletin began publication in 1980. The series contains a complete run of the ICPSR Bulletin from 1980 to the present. Two other newsletters can be found in this series: The ICPSR Micronews, published from 1983 until 1984, and News, Notes, and Updates, issued from 1980 to 1981.
  - Annual reports
    - ICPR Annual Report, 1962/1963-1974/1975, 11 folders (Box 1)
    - ICPSR Annual Report, 1975/1976-2004/2005, 21 folders (Box 1)
  - Bookmarks
    - ICPSR Social Science Data for Secondary Analysis, undated (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - General Information on the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research undated (Box 1)
    - Mini Courses, undated, 1985-1997 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous undated, 1980-1997 (Box 1)
    - Website Resources undated (Box 1)
  - Catalogs
    - Data Available: Historical Archive, International Relations Archive, Survey Research Archive, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Inventory of Data Resources, 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Annotated Archival Holdings, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Guide to Resources and Services
      - 1970-1971/1972, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1972-1991, 10 folders (Box 2)
      - 1991/1992-1996/1997, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Manuals
    - Data Preparation Manual, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Guide to Social Science Data Preparation and Archiving
      - 1997 (Box 4)
      - 2000 (Box 4)
  - Newsletters
    - Informational Mailings, 1976-1981, 6 folders (Box 4)
    - ICPSR Bulletin, 1980-2006, 27 folders (Box 4)
    - The ICPSR Micronews, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
    - News, Notes and Updates, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications series contains brochures, catalogs and newsletters from the ICPSR's component archives: the International Relations Archive, the National Archive of Computerized Data on Aging, the National Archive of Criminal Justice Data (formerly the National Criminal Justice Archive and Information Network), and the National Institute of Justice. This series also includes bulletins and syllabi from the ICPSR's summer course, called first the Summer Program, then the Training Program, and then the Summer Course in Quantitative Methods.
  - International Relations Archive
    - Catalogs
      - Studies Available from the International Relations Archive, 1971 (Box 5)
  - National Archive of Computerized Data on Aging
    - Catalogs
      - Data Collections, 1985-1997, 10 folders (Box 5)
    - Newsletters
      - Bulletin, 1984-1998, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - National Archive of Criminal Justice Data (supersedes National Criminal Justice Archive and Information Network)
    - Catalogs
      - Criminal Justice Data Collections, 1989-1997, 5 folders (Box 5)
    - Newsletters
      - Newsletter 1990-1996 (Box 5)
  - National Criminal Justice Archive and Information Network (precedes National Archive of Criminal Justice Data)
    - Catalogs
      - Data Collections, 1985-1988, 5 folders (Box 5)
    - Newsletters
      - CJAIN, 1983-1989 (Box 5)
  - National Institute of Justice
    - Brochures
      - Data Resources Program of the National Institute of Justice, 1993-1998, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Catalogs
      - Data Resources of the National Institute of Justice, 1992-1996, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Summer Course in Quantitative Methods (supersedes Training Program)
    - Bulletins
      - Summer Course in Quantitative Methods, 1983-1999, 10 folders (Box 6)
    - Flyers 1983-1989 (Box 6)
    - Syllabi 1983-1997, 8 folders (Box 6)
  - Summer Program (precedes Training Program)
    - Bulletins
      - Summer Program, 1970-1975, 1977-1979, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Training Program (supersedes Summer Program, precedes Summer Course in Quantitative Methods)
    - Bulletins
      - Training Program, 1980-1982, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Syllabi 1980-1982, 3 folders (Box 6)